The CIA has taken actions, right?
听说CIA出动了？
It seems like we are under their watch,
好像被监视了
but he said not to worry.
不过他说没有问题
Is that Japanese reliable?
那个日本人可以信任吗
Yes.
可以
After all, he's Japan's legendary hitman.
他在日本被称为传说中的杀手
But he's not cheap.
不过酬金可不低啊
Isn't that the saying, "Nothing can't be fixed with money," right?
这就是所谓的有钱能使鬼推磨吗
Yea.
是啊
This time, I'll let that guy understand
这下就能让那个男人也彻底体会到
there's something in this world that's far worse than death!
这个世上还有比死亡更痛苦的事了
I don't know anything!
我什么都不知道
I only drove the truck out of the port.
我只是从港口把卡车开走而已
They didn't even tell me where to go!
他们甚至连目的地都没有告诉我
Who hired you?
我是问你的雇主是谁
I've told you! I don't know!
我都说了不知道啊
All the instructions came over the phone!
对方只是用电话下达指示
Aren't you known as "The Courier Joe"?
你不是号称「走私达人乔」吗
Why would a pro like you agree to do
你这样的专家会为这样一通电话
such a risky job just through one phone call?
就接下这么危险的工作吗
I didn't know at all there were bombs in the truck!
我根本不知道卡车里面有炸弹啊
Stop lying!
少在这和我扯
(Detective Conan The Disappearance of Conan Edogawa: The Worst Two Days in History)
名侦探柯南 江户川柯南失踪事件 史上最糟糕的两天
I'm a high school detective, Shinichi Kudo.
我是高中生侦探工藤新一
While visiting an amusement park with Ran Mouri, my childhood friend and classmate,
在和同级的青梅竹马毛利兰去游乐场玩时
I witnessed a man in black in the midst of a suspicious transaction.
目击了黑衣人可疑的交易现场
Totally caught up in watching the deal,
看得出神的我
I failed to notice his partner sneaking up behind me.
没注意到从背后接近的另一名同伙
That man forced me to ingest a poison.
我被那个男人灌下毒药
When I woke up,
没想到醒来之后
my body had shrunk!
身体竟然缩小了
If those guys found out that Shinichi Kudo was still alive,
如果被那些家伙发现工藤新一还活着
they'd come after me again
不仅我的性命堪忧
and put those around me at risk.
身边的人也会被危及
Listening to Professor Agasa's suggestion, I hid my real identity,
因此在阿笠博士的建议下 我隐瞒了身份
and came up with the alias,
当兰问及名字时
Conan Edogawa, when pressed by Ran.
情急之下我谎称自己是「江户川柯南」
In order to collect information on those people,
为了收集那些家伙的情报
I moved in with Ran, whose father is a detective.
我便寄住在父亲是侦探的小兰家中
These are my current classmates,
他们是我现在的同学
Genta,
元太
Mitsuhiko
光彦
and Ayumi.
步美
They formed the Detective Boys,
他们建立了少年侦探团
and even included me into it without asking me.
还擅自把我也拉入伙
And
然后
this guy is Kogoro Mouri.
这位大叔是毛利小五郎
Needless to explain any further,
不用我说明也都知道了吧
these two items are Professor Agasa's inventions.
这两个都是阿笠博士的发明
He invented all sorts
博士为了变小的我
of unique and novel tools for the shrunken me.
接连不断地发明了举世无双的道具
The Anywhere Ball Dispensing Belt
足球射出腰带
conveniently dispenses
只要按下腰带按钮
an inflated soccer at the press
足球就会膨胀并弹出
of a button.
非常便利
By the way,
顺便一提
other than the professor, there is someone else who knows my real identity,
知道我真实身份的除了博士还有别人
Ai Haibara.
灰原哀
Her real name is Shiho Miyano.
本名宫野志保
She was originally a member of the Black Organization,
她原本是黑衣男子的同伙
but she took the same poison I had
逃出组织的时候
when she escaped from the organization,
吃了同样的药
and her body also shrunk.
身体也缩小了
Haibara thus moved into the professor's house,
就这样 加上和博士一起生活的灰原
and enrolled in first grade with us.
我们开始了小学一年级的生活
Even though my body has shrunk, I'm still that sharp-minded,
身体缩小头脑依旧灵活
intelligent, and unbeaten detective!
无所不知的名侦探
Only one truth will prevail!
真相永远只有一个
It's coming, Mitsuhiko!
开始了 光彦
Nice kick!
好球
Here I go!
我要射门了
Go!
上吧
Ayumi-chan, look up!
步美 上面
Nice catch, Ayumi-chan!
接得好 步美
We are not done yet!
还没完呢
Yeah!
太棒了
I'm ready!
好
Yesterday around 10 p.m.,
昨晚10点左右
the police received a report that a delivery truck driving in the residential area
警方接到了杯户街住宅区行驶的快递公司的卡车中
of Haido-cho contained a large quantity of bombs.
装着大量炸弹的通报
The police investigation found
警方展开了调查
that it carried plastic explosives that are suspected to be smuggled items.
在货物中发现了疑似走私塑胶炸弹的东西
I cracked my glasses while playing soccer.
踢足球的时候弄坏了
I heard of that.
我听说了
The professor is preparing a new pair.
博士正在准备新的
It's the shoes' fault.
都怪这鞋啦
I kicked the ball too hard because of the malfunction.
因为故障 球都不知道飞到哪里去了
Talk about my bad luck lately!
最近真是不走运啊
- Where's the professor? - Disguised as cookie cans...
-博士呢 -…伪装成曲奇罐样子的包裹
The bath's broken. He's repairing it.
浴室也出问题了正在修呢
Based on the investigation,
根据警方的调查
the bombs were found on a foreign cargo ship moored at the docks.
卡车上的炸弹是从停在港口边的外国货船上运下的
The place where the bombs were found
说起来离这很近啊
is pretty close from here, isn't it?
发现炸弹的地点
Yeah.
是啊
But it shouldn't be the organization.
但如果是组织的人
They wouldn't make such a mistake.
不会犯这种错误的吧
Well, I hope so.
啊 希望如此吧
Sorry!
抱歉
Looks like I need more time to fix the bath.
浴室好像要再花点时间才能修好
Eh? Use our bathroom?
我家的浴室？
Sure you can.
当然可以啦
Why don't we all go to the bath house together?
啊 要不要大家一起去澡堂啊
The bath house?
澡堂？
It's nice to go to a big bath house every now and then!
偶尔也想泡泡大浴池不是吗
Dad, are you coming with us?
爸爸你去吗
I'm too shocked to go anywhere.
我受了打击动不了了
Those are just rumors, you know?
那不过是绯闻吧
But what if it's true?
要是真的怎么办啊
Let's go without him.
我们三个去吧
Conan-kun, would you like to join us in the ladies' side?
柯南要不要来女澡堂呀
Just kidding!
开玩笑啦
Welcome!
欢迎光临
Hey,
喂
are you done yet?
好了吗
I need a little longer.
还有一会儿
That's a nice feeling, isn't it?
那样感觉也不错呢
Hey, Ai-chan, is there a boy you like in school?
小哀你在学校有喜欢的人吗
I'll never get romantically involved with a little boy.
我是不会和小孩子谈恋爱的
I see...
这样啊
Hey.
我说
Is that locker yours, Oji-san?
那个柜子是叔叔你专用的吗
No...
不
Well... I guess.
啊 算是吧
Little boy.
小朋友
Did you come here alone?
你是一个人来的吗
Conan-kun!
柯南
Do you feel lonely there all by yourself?
你一个人会不会很孤单啊
I'm doing fine!
没关系
I just met someone I know!
刚刚遇见了一个认识的哥哥
Someone you know?
认识的哥哥是谁啊
Someone you know, too, Ran-neechan!
是小兰姐姐也认识的人
Conan-kun fell?
柯南他
Yes. A man he knows drove him to the hospital already.
嗯 一个认识他的男子开车送他去医院了
Which hospital?
哪里的医院啊
I'm not sure. It should be a hospital nearby, I think.
不知道 估计是这附近的医院吧
Sorry!
不好意思啊
I should have asked them which hospital he was going to.
当时如果问一下是哪里的医院就好了
It's alright. We'll go look for him.
没关系 我去找一找
Let's go, Ai-chan!
走吧 小哀
I thought we were going to the hospital.
不是要去医院吗
That kid saw what was inside the locker.
这个小鬼 看见柜子里面的东西了
You are one of us, aren't you?
你是我们这边的人吧
I'm surprised you can tell.
你连这都知道了
I heard someone was keeping an eye on things.
我听说有监视的人
Your fierce gaze
太明显了啊
gave you away.
你眼神太凶了
What do we do now?
接下来怎么办
Let's ask for instructions first.
总之先请示一下吧
What are you laughing about?
那你又能干什么
You are also just a minion who takes orders!
你不也只是个按指示行动的小混混吗
Don't forget that I'm also helping to clean up your mess here.
我可是随机应变帮你擦了屁股啊
No wonder you are known as the "Ad-libbing Tatsu."
真不愧是即兴表演龙啊
It's because of your tattoo.
是你的纹身
I've heard rumors about you.
我曾听过你的传闻
No matter what unexpected situations you face,
不管发生什么意料之外的情况
you can think on your feet
都能当机立断见机行事
and finish the job successfully.
完美地完成工作
The "Ad-libbing Tatsu" with a dragon tattoo,
身上纹着一条龙的即兴表演龙
you're famous in the underworld.
在黑道上可是很有名的
I don't know who you are talking about.
不 不知道你是在说谁啊
Hey...
我说
Who are you guys?
叔叔你们是谁啊
Ah, you hit your head in the bath house.
你 你在澡堂里撞到了头
You are Conan-kun, right?
你是叫柯南吧
Conan?
柯南？
Do you know your name?
你知道自己的名字吗
Name?
名字？
Professor!
博士
How's Conan-kun doing?
怎么样啊 柯南还好吧
Apparently he wasn't brought to this hospital.
他们说没有被送到这里来
What?
什么
It's weird, right?
很奇怪吧
This is the nearest hospital available.
这里明明是最近的医院啊
The other hospitals in this neighborhood...
要说这附近其它医院的话
It's from Shinichi!
是新一发来的
Oh, I see!
什么嘛
The person he met was Shinichi.
认识的大哥哥原来是新一啊
He says his injuries are not severe, so don't worry.
他说伤势没什么大碍不用担心
Look.
你看
(Injuries aren't severe, so don't worry. We'll go grab something to eat together.)
-我的伤势并不严重所以别担心了 -正要跟相熟的哥哥一起去吃饭
Ah, really?
这样啊
That's good.
那就好
But sending a message like this is so rude.
不过这算什么啊 发这样的短信
If they're having a meal, why not invite us?
去吃饭的话 把我们也叫上不就好了
- The number you are calling cannot be reached at the moment. - Hello, Shinichi...
-您所拨打的电话不在服务区 -啊 新一
Fine!
是吗
Let's go home.
回去吧
I gave him a powerful sleeping pill.
是强效的安眠药
He won't wake up any time soon.
估计他短时间内都不会醒过来了
I sent a text to the girl, Ran-neechan, who went to the bath house with him,
我也给那个在女浴室的小兰姐姐
so that's settled for the moment.
发过短信了 暂时没什么问题了
That boy's memories seem to be in a mess.
那小鬼好像记忆混乱了
If he'd forget about everything, then that would be great.
要是能全都忘了就好了
You are "Locksmith Maru", aren't you?
你是开锁高手马尔吧
What's a pro burglar like you doing here?
盗窃的专家在这里做什么
I just followed directions to pick the locks here and prepare the sleeping pill.
他只是让我打开这里的门并准备好安眠药
I'm going back now!
我要回去了
You can't do that!
不行啊
Why?
为 为什么
Who knows?
我怎么知道
The text says to wait here for orders after putting that kid out.
短信上说让小孩睡着后所有人在这里等着
Damn it.
可恶
You don't know who you're working for, either?
你也不知道是谁指示的你吗
The request only came over the phone.
我只是在电话里接了委托
You call this a "request"? Come on!
这不是什么委托吧
He's blackmailing you, right?
你有什么把柄被抓住了
At any rate, it's best to obediently follow the instructions.
总之老实听从指示在这里待着是为自己好
After being in this business for years,
毕竟常年在这种世界生活
I have this feeling that
我有预感
whoever is directing us must be someone quite frightening.
不论是谁 指使我们的一定是个相当恐怖的人
Tomorrow morning, Nihorika's Prime Minister Babel will visit Japan.
明日清晨 尼保利加国的巴贝尔首相将抵达日本
In the press conference, the Cabinet Chief Secretary talked about the issues that would be discussed at tomorrow's summit.
内阁官房长官在记者招待会上对明天举行的首脑会谈作了说明
Because Nihorika's air attack on Arattan
由于此前尼保利加国对阿拉单国的空袭
led to a dangerous situation at the border...
导致周边地区安全环境恶化
Hey, I'm starving from shock.
喂 我因为受打击肚子饿死了
Please hurry up and cook.
快去做饭吧
Just go grab something at Poirot downstairs.
去下面的波洛吃点什么吧
Anyway,
总之
I'm in a terrible mood, so I'm going to bed!
我心情不好要睡觉了
Seriously, what's wrong with her?
真是的 什么嘛
She's becoming more and more like Eri.
越来越像英理了
Come in!
你好
Excuse me.
不好意思
We're closed for the day...
今天已经关门了…
I see.
是这样啊
I'll come back tomorrow then.
那我明天再来拜访吧
No, no, no!
啊 不不不
The policy's different for pretty ladies.
美女另当别论
It's okay. You made it just in time!
没关系 刚好还有点时间
So you want to find out if your husband's having an affair?
是您丈夫的外遇调查啊
Yes.
是的
He won't admit it,
虽然他本人否定了
but I don't believe him because he's been acting very suspiciously lately.
但他的行为很奇怪 我无法相信
I'm limited in my ability
我自己调查的话
to investigate on my own.
人力物力都有限
And I don't want to interfere with my job and trouble the company,
而且也不想影响工作给公司添麻烦
so I came to seek your expertise.
所以才想拜托专业人士
I see.
原来如此
Do you have any idea who he's seeing?
外遇对象您心里有数吗
No.
没有
It's just that, when I was tidying up his car this morning,
但是今天早上打扫他的车时
I could smell a woman's perfume.
闻到了女性香水的味道
What's your husband's occupation?
您丈夫的职业是什么
He's currently looking for a job.
现在正在找工作
He's having an affair while letting such
让这么漂亮的妻子工作
a beautiful wife work to support the family.
如果自己还搞外遇
How unforgivable!
那真是不能原谅
Understood!
我知道了
Let's start our investigation at the bath house where you last saw him!
我们现在就去你最后看见你丈夫的澡堂吧
Okay.
好
We must move fast!
必须要快点才行
And after that...
在那之后
how about having dinner with me?
要不要去哪里吃个饭啊
As expected,
果然
the signal hasn't moved from the bath house.
还在澡堂没有动啊
This means his belongings are still there.
也就是他的东西还在那里放着
His belongings are still there?
东西还在那里
So he's not even dressed?
那他没穿衣服吗
Let's go.
走吧
What? His mother?
他  他妈妈？
Yes, just a while ago. A woman said she was here for her son's belongings
是的 就在刚才 说来取他儿子的东西
and that he was fine now!
还说那孩子没摔伤
It's moving.
动了
This speed... She must be in a car.
这个速度 是汽车
What is it, Ai-kun?
怎 怎么了 小哀
Follow the signal, Professor!
博士你去追他的东西
What about you, Ai-kun?
小哀你呢
Just go!
快去
So, let's go over there first.
那就先去那边吧
Good evening!
晚上好
You are that four-eyed boy's...
你是那个眼镜小鬼的…
Who are you, Onee-san?
姐姐你是谁啊
Look, I'm busy. Don't disturb me!
喂 我正在工作别捣乱
I'm hungry.
我饿了
Then go home.
那就赶紧回家
But the professor isn't home right now.
但是博士出门了不在家啊
But he just...
但是刚刚…
Then let's have dinner together.
那就一起吃饭吧
Really?
可以吗
Thank you!
谢谢
But this will get in the way of our work...
但是会妨碍工作啊
It's alright.
没关系
There's nothing to hide anyway.
我也没什么见不得人的
Let's go.
走吧
So this is the building where your husband used to work?
这里就是你丈夫以前上班的公寓啊
We're moving soon.
本来打算马上就搬走的
He used to work as a handyman.
但他以前是给人家做杂工的
Please come in.
请进
There are lots of things to throw away,
还有很多需要处理的东西
so we haven't finished tidying up yet.
还没有整理好
I see.
原来如此
This place is pretty convenient for an affair, isn't it?
不过这真是个方便搞外遇的地方啊
Your husband looks like an honest man, though.
明明是个看起来很认真的人啊
Men having affairs all seem morally upstanding.
男人都是很认真地搞外遇的
What's in your bag?
那个包里装了什么啊
Hey!
喂
It's for work.
工作用的东西
I'm a magazine editor.
我是杂志的编辑
I have to go back to work later tonight.
一会儿还必须回公司一趟
That's tough.
那真是辛苦啊
I've got a deadline.
因为到截稿期了
I see.
原来如此
He's really not here.
果然不在啊
Wait a moment!
喂 我说
It's unlocked.
门是开着的
Hey!
喂
Don't wander around on your own!
别一个人跑来跑去的
The professor asked me to go home.
博士叫我了 我回去了
What about dinner?
不吃饭了吗
I'll pass.
不用了
Ah, Ai-kun,
啊  小哀
what are you doing here?
你为什么在这
I was just about to ask you that.
博士你才是为什么在这
I was following the signal, which led me to this building.
我 我追着他的东西过来 就到这个公寓了
Ah, it's coming out.
啊 出来了
Let me see.
给我
Hey, are you done yet?
喂 好了吗
It's the woman at the bath house earlier.
那个女人是之前在澡堂的
Follow her!
追
Speaking of which, does working as a handyman
话说回来 打杂工这种工作
really this profitable?
那么好赚钱吗
Since you're able to move into such a high-class apartment.
能住得起这么高级的公寓
Who knows...
不知道
Detective work shouldn't be too different from being a handyman,
侦探明明和打杂工差不多啊
but actually it's like night and day.
简直天差地别啊
Ma'am!
夫人
Yes?
什么
Did you know about this room?
你知道有这房间吗
I see, a handyman, was it?
原来如此 「打杂工」啊
Ma'am,
夫人
your husband probably wasn't having an affair.
你先生多半是没有出轨
What on earth is going on?
究竟是怎么回事
I don't know, but...
不知道 但是
I have a bad feeling about this.
有种不好的预感
Kondo?
你说近藤
Yeah.
是的
The person who gave me the truck keys warned me
把卡车钥匙交给我的人说过
not to make any mistakes,
不要出差错
because the person directing us is Kondo-san!
指使我们的是近藤
Kondo, you mean that legendary hitman?
近藤是那个什么传说中的杀手吗
That's just an urban legend.
那只是都市传说罢了
Can you prove that this person really exists?
还是说有证据能证明他存在吗
The police
警 警方
will protect me, right?
会保护我的吧
Come in.
请进
Sir, sorry to interrupt.
乔先生 打扰一下
What is it?
怎么了
The number of bombs that we found did not match the intelligence provided by the CIA.
果然CIA的情报和实际发现的炸弹数量不一样
What? Are you certain?
什么 确定吗
Yes, we've checked many times already,
嗯 反复核对很多遍了
but we're still missing a few.
果然还是少了一些
Damn it,
可恶
so there are still other bombs out there?
这么说还有其它的炸弹吗
What do we do now, Ai-kun?
接下来怎么办 小哀
I'll go take a look around.
我去看看情况
Stay here, Professor.
博士你留在这里
You've got to be careful!
千万别勉强啊
I know.
我知道
Prepare to move,
准备转移了
and bring the kid.
把小孩也带上
Who are you?
你 你是谁啊
It's better for both of us if you don't know.
你不用知道 这样对彼此都好
I only followed instructions to pick up the kid's belongings.
我只是按照指示取回了小孩的东西
You guys caused this mess!
都是你的失误
You even forgot this!
连这个都忘记拿回来了
You don't know who you're working for, either?
你也不知道我们是在为谁做事吗
I have a rough idea.
能猜出个大概
Who is it?
是谁
My work here should be done!
我 我的工作应该已经完成了
That's right.
没错
All of you here are done.
你们的工作已经结束了
Let's go, Kondo-san.
走吧 近藤先生
Professor! I heard gunshots.
博士 我听到了枪声
Hurry and call the police!
快点报警
Gun...Gunshots?
枪 枪声？
Hurry!
快点
Ai-kun!
小哀
Follow that car!
追那辆车
Oh, okay!
哦 好
Maybe the plan is to use the kid.
大概是要利用他吧
"Use"?
利用？
This Beetle behind us is really suspicious.
那辆甲壳虫真让人生疑
The radar isn't working!
雷达不动了
It's malfunctioning again?
又有故障了吗
Don't get too close.
别太接近了
We can't let them find out we are tailing them!
只能在不暴露的前提下跟踪了
Understood.
知道了
Where exactly are they bringing him?
究竟要把他带到哪去啊
Don't worry.
别着急
If they wanted to kill him, they'd have done it by now.
要想解决他的话早就下手了
Professor!
博士
What?
怎 怎么了
Hey, that's dangerous!
喂 很危险啊
Ai-kun!
小哀
It's this place, right?
是这里吧
Someone probably just mistook the sound of firecrackers for gunshots.
估计是把鞭炮声听错了吧
Yeah, it could be it.
嗯 差不多就是这样
Nihorika's Prime Minister Babel landed
尼保利加国的巴贝尔首相
at Tokyo Haneda Airport by government plane this morning.
今早乘政府专机抵达东京羽田机场
This afternoon, the Prime Minister will visit the Imperial Palace with his family.
在这之后 首相将于中午与家人一同访问皇居
Poor thing.
真可怜啊
You'll feel better soon.
马上就会好起来的
Mom and Dad are here for you.
爸爸妈妈都陪着你呢
It's alright.
没事的
I'll bring you breakfast.
我去拿早餐过来
I'm scared...
我好怕啊
I'm going to Shinichi's before school.
我先去新一家一趟再去学校
Jeez!
真是的
Someone's in a bad mood today.
什么啊 一大早就这么不高兴
Of course!
当然了
I went to bed yesterday without eating anything. I'm starving now!
昨天什么都没吃就睡觉了 饿死了
Plus, Conan-kun went off with Shinichi and didn't come back!
柯南也是和新一走了就没有回来
I didn't eat anything, either.
我也什么都没吃呢
Will you cook something?
去做点什么吧
Like I said, I'm going out now!
我不是说了我要出门了吗
Gosh! What an unfilial daughter!
真是的 真是个不孝女
Doesn't even pity her father for working overnight!
明明老爸都熬夜工作了
Conan-kun's really late...
柯南真晚啊
Ai-chan hasn't arrived, either.
小哀也还没有来
Are they not coming today?
是不是请假了
Can't believe it!
真是的
We agreed that we'd go to Yokohama together after school.
亏我们还约了放学后一起去横滨的
Yokohama?
横滨？
We talked about it yesterday during soccer, remember?
昨天踢足球的时候不是决定好了的吗
The Red Brick Warehouse is having a Kamen Yaiba exhibit,
去红砖仓库看假面超人展
and the professor will drive us there.
坐博士的车去
Ah, right!
啊 对哦
I hope Conan didn't forget
不知道柯南这家伙
to ask the professor.
有没有好好拜托博士啊
I hope he didn't.
有的话就好了
Yeah.
是啊
A Kamen Yaiba exhibit?
假面超人展？
What do you mean?
怎 怎么一回事
Apparently the Prime Minister's children are big fans,
首相的孩子好像是假面超人的粉丝
and want to go there.
说是怎么都要去
You've got to be kidding!
真是受不了
It won't be announced as an official activity.
本来就不作为公共活动对外发表
Only his wife and children are going,
只有夫人和孩子去
the Prime Minister won't be accompanying them.
首相不去
Where is it?
在哪里
I heard that it's at the Red Brick Warehouse in Yokohama.
好  好像是在横滨的红砖仓库
Yokohama?!
横滨？
Yes!
是 是的
Jeez, how troublesome.
真是添麻烦
Alright. Understood.
好了 我知道了
I'll request assistance from the Kanagawa Prefectural Police.
由我来向神奈川县警请求协助
Now, go back to work.
你继续工作
Yes.
是
Can't you cook something better?
你就不能做点稍微像样一点的东西吗
I'm not a cook.
我又不是厨师
Is it not good enough for a genius conman like you, Nana-san?
没办法合天才诈骗人娜娜小姐你的胃口啊
So you know my name.
你知道我的名字啊
You are the genius hacker M indeed!
真不愧是天才黑客M
How did you find out who I am?
你怎么知道我是谁的
I've just found out.
刚知道的
It's about time.
差不多到时间了吧
Here's the kid's bag.
这是那个孩子的包
To keep his family quiet, precautions have been taken.
为了避免那个孩子的家人弄出什么动静已经采取措施了
What's going on? Why aren't you at school?
你怎么回事 没去学校吗
Shinichi sent another stupid text,
新一给我发了条莫名其妙的短信
saying something about going to the Kamen Yaiba exhibit in Yokohama.
说什么要去横滨的假面超人展哦
Look at this!
什么啊那是
Yokohama?
横滨？
It's a place named Red Brick Warehouse.
一个叫红砖仓库的地方
I'm going to check it out.
我走了
The Red Brick Warehouse...
红砖仓库
Eh? So her husband is the legendary hitman?
这么说 她的丈夫就是那个传说中的杀手
Yes.
嗯
After receiving a request,
接下委托后
he'd eliminate the target
设定完美的计划
through careful planning
完全抹杀目标
and dispose of the body without a trace. He's a professional hitman indeed.
连尸体都不会让人找到的专业杀手
Information and notes related to Kondo's crimes
记录了那个近藤所犯案件的资料和笔记
were stacked in her husband's workroom.
在她老公工作的地方有一大堆
Are the articles in this kind of magazine even reliable?
这种杂志上写的能信吗
I don't know.
不清楚
Anyway, there was a new document on the table in that room,
总之桌子上就放了一份全新的文件
containing instructions for bombs
里面放有炸弹的使用说明
and schematics of the Red Brick Warehouse.
还有红砖仓库的示意图
Suspicious, isn't it?
很可疑吧
Why not call the police?
还是报警吧
We have to find some concrete evidence first.
那得再有一些确定的证据啊
Otherwise I wouldn't be able to do my job right.
不然我也无法大展身手了
Have you told that madam?
和那位太太说过这事了吗
She went to the office for work.
她说有工作要回下公司
I lost contact with her after that.
那之后就联系不上她了
How poor she is!
真可怜啊 那位太太
(Injuries aren't severe, so don't worry. We'll go grab something to eat together.)
-我的伤势并不严重所以别担心了 -正要跟相熟的哥哥一起去吃饭
Hello, Shinichi...
喂 新一
The number you are calling cannot be reached at the moment.
您所拨打的电话…
Poor me, too.
我也很可怜
Why are men so selfish?
为什么男的净做一些任性的事情
Gosh!
真是的
That's dangerous!
很危险的啊
What are you doing?
你在做什么
I was in an accident.
出车祸了
Could you give me a ride?
可以载我一下吗
Sorry, find another car.
不好意思你搭别的车吧
One, two,
准备
Kamen Yaiba!
假面超人
Even though it was a rush job,
虽然是突然接的活
the images from the event are very clear
但是现场的摄像头拍得很清楚嘛
and the sound is fine too.
声音也没什么问题
The remote activation was already tested at the abandoned factory.
远程操控也已经在废旧工厂里演习过了
It won't be long before the targets move into position.
目标马上就要到了
And the brat carrying the bomb is just standing there obediently...
背着炸弹的小鬼也一个人老老实实地站在那里
But I'm still a bit reluctant.
但总觉得有些不舒服
Is it because the targets are children from the very beginning?
难道是从一开始目标就是小孩的原因？
There isn't much of a difference,
不过本质上并没有区别
but having me press the switch...
只是让我来按开关有点
Here they come!
哦 来了来了
15 meters to go!
还有15米
It'll explode as soon as I press this button!
按下这里就会砰的一下爆炸了
10 meters.
10米
7 meters.
7米
5 meters.
5米
Conan-kun,
柯南
I finally found you!
终于找到你了
Where's Shinichi?
新一在哪里
Who are you, Onee-chan?
姐姐你是谁
3 meters.
3米
2 meters.
2米
1 meter.
1米
You don't like the food?
不好吃吗
No...
没有
You don't love me anymore?
你不喜欢我了吗
Why would you ask that?
为什么这么问
You've been acting weird these days.
这几天你的样子都很奇怪
I'm a little concerned.
我很担心你
You think too much.
不是的
Sorry for making you worry.
抱歉让你担心了
Is it marriage blues?
婚前抑郁吗
No...
不是
Sorry,
不好意思
I have an appointment with someone.
我和人约了见面
Is that so?
这样啊
I'm really sorry.
真的不好意思
It's okay.
没关系
The delivery truck will arrive shortly.
快递公司的车子马上就会经过
The package will be placed in the corner ahead.
会把东西扔在前边的角落里
Take it and leave immediately.
你把那个装上车 然后马上离开
What's inside?
是什么东西
You don't need to know that.
你不用知道
Anyway, there's been a small problem.
总之出了一点问题
That truck has been tailed by the police,
那辆卡车已经被警察给盯上了
so I need you to take the package to a safe place.
所以希望你能把那样东西送到安全的地方
Is that all?
只是这样吗
Yes.
是的
If everything goes well, your work will be all over.
进展顺利的话你的工作就到此为止了
Are you ready?
准备好了吗
Yes. 4 was all I could fit.
装了4个就满了
It can't fit any more.
再装也装不下了
Good.
好咧
Throw it out the window
在下一个转弯口的时候
at the next turn.
把这个包扔到外面去
Do it without attracting attention.
注意不要引人注目
It's out. Now what?
扔掉了 接下来要干嘛
That's all.
可以了
Eh? So you just wanted me to move a bunch of cookies?
只是让我送一下曲奇罐就可以了吗
You really don't live up to your name "the Courier Joe", do you?
你真是对不起「走私达人乔」的称号
Haven't you noticed that the police have been following you?
难道你没发现被警察跟踪了吗
Where's the package?
东西呢
What's this?
这算什么
I left it in a locker at the bath house.
我放在澡堂的柜子里了
That place was swarming with cops earlier.
那边都是警察
I couldn't just walk around with such a suspicious package.
总不能拿着奇怪的东西在那闲晃吧
It's at the men's side.
我不可能进去啊
How am I supposed to get in?
那是男澡堂吧
I didn't expect that a woman to show up.
没想到来接头的竟然是个女的
You heard that, right?
听到了吧就是这样
Yes, yes. Understood.
嗯 嗯 我知道了
You're done for today.
你今天应该是可以回去了
"Today"? Is there more?
今天？ 是说以后还有工作的意思吗
Who knows?
谁知道呢
Don't ask me.
不要问我
Just wait for further instructions.
你等指示吧
I've sent a guy to collect the package.
我让一个男人去取那个东西了
I need you to keep an eye on him.
你监视他
Keep an eye on him?
监视？
Blend in with the customers
你装成客人
and see if he gets it away safely.
看他是否能顺利将东西取走
If anything happens, take care of it!
出什么差错的话你想办法应对
Why won't you let me get it myself?
为什么不直接让我去取
I have my reasons.
我自有考虑
I won't force you to tell.
我并没有期待你会告诉我
That's better for both of us.
这对彼此都好
This is your last job, I promise.
我答应你 做完这次就放你自由
One adult.
一位成人
Welcome.
欢迎光临
Hey.
我说
Is that locker yours, Oji-san?
那个柜子是叔叔你专用的吗
Are you okay, little boy?
小朋友你没事吧
Hey, you!
喂 你
Let's take the boy to the hospital.
你帮我一起把那个孩子送到医院
Please.
拜托了
What are you laughing about?
那你又能干什么
You are also just a minion who takes orders!
你不也只是个按指示行动的小混混吗
Don't forget that I'm also helping to clean up your mess here.
我可是随机应变帮你擦了屁股啊
No wonder you are known as the "Ad-libbing Tatsu."
真不愧是即兴表演龙啊
It's because of your tattoo.
是你的纹身
Hey...
我说
Who are you guys?
叔叔你们是谁啊
Ah, you hit your head in the bath house.
你 你在澡堂里撞到了头
You are Conan-kun, right?
你是叫柯南吧
Conan?
柯南？
Do you know your name?
你知道自己的名字吗
Name?
名字？
Where am I?
这里是哪里
I don't know, either.
叔叔也不知道
You really don't remember anything?
你真的什么都想不起来吗
Boy, this medicine is for your head.
小朋友 这是对脑袋很有效的药
Take it and sleep for a bit.
吃完睡一下吧
Okay.
嗯
That's right.
没错
All of you here are done.
你们的工作已经结束了
Let's go, Kondo-san.
走吧 近藤先生
The kid doesn't remember anything.
这孩子失忆了
Leaving him here should be fine.
放在这里不管他也没什么问题吧
Our order is to bring him with us.
上头说把他也带走
It's not your decision to make.
不是由你来决定的
When this is over, will you kill me too?
等我做完工作之后也要杀我灭口吗
Depends on the instructions.
如果有这样的命令的话
If I don't do it, I'd be silenced instead.
否则我就要被灭口了
What are you being blackmailed over?
你是被抓住了什么把柄才被威胁的
Nothing as major as yours.
没你的弱点厉害
I'd never think that the legendary hitman, Kondo,
有谁会知道传说中的杀手居然
is just a man who lets his targets go.
一直都只是在放人逃跑
Instead of killing the targets, you secretly set them all free.
假装杀人其实把所有的人都给放走了
It must be pretty lucrative,
你应该赚了不少钱吧
since both sides have to pay you.
毕竟你两边都收
How did you find out?
为什么你会知道这件事情
He told me that.
上头告诉我的
Probably to prevent me from being scared of you.
大概是不想让我对你产生多余的恐惧
What about the kid?
他们打算用这个孩子做什么
Who knows?
谁知道啊
Maybe the plan is to use the kid.
大概是要利用他吧
"Use"?
利用？
This Beetle behind us is suspicious.
那辆甲壳虫真让人生疑
He's asleep?
睡了？
Yeah.
是的
We'll have to spend the night here for instructions.
今晚我们要在这里待命
How about some wine?
你也来一杯？
Sure.
好的
I'm surprised you can be so calm about this.
你的那份沉着冷静真是了不起啊
At this point, there's no point panicking.
事到如今干着急也无济于事
You're awake, right?
你是醒着的对吧
I put the sleeping pill you'd thrown away inside that woman's drink.
我把你丢掉的安眠药给那个女人喝了
She's sound asleep.
她睡得很熟
Don't be afraid.
你不用害怕
I'll let you go.
我会放你走的
So get up quietly.
悄悄地起来
What will happen to you, Oji-san.
叔叔你会怎样
You are used because they've got something on you, right?
你应该是授人以柄所以才被利用了吧
Yes.
嗯
Inside the locker at the bath house
澡堂的柜子里面是
were bombs, right?
炸弹对吧
I saw on the news that the bombs were put into cookie cans.
是用曲奇罐伪装起来的 我在新闻中看到过
Oji-san, do you really have no idea what they are doing this for?
叔叔你真的不知道做这些的目的是什么吗
A lot of people were given instructions,
很多人都被利用了
but no one knows the whole plan.
谁都不知道真正的计划
That's why I have to find the mastermind.
所以叔叔必须找出那个最坏的人
After you get out, go to the police...
你从这里出去之后去找警察
If I disappear,
我不见了的话
you'll be suspected.
叔叔你会被怀疑的
What's more...
而且
Hello!
你好
So you're that famous Kondo-san.
你就是那个有名的杀手近藤啊
Who are you?
你呢
Your teammate.
是你的团队伙伴哟
Are you...
你
Sorry to disappoint you, but I'm not the leader.
不好意思我可不是头头
We can watch him with this.
用这个来监视他就好了
So you can go to sleep.
你可以去休息了
Hello? Yes.
喂 是的
Yeah.
嗯
The Red Brick Warehouse?
红砖仓库？
There was a ticket for an event there
在那个孩子的衣服口袋里
in that kid's pocket.
有在那办的活动入场券
Many kids will go,
会有很多孩子去那里的
so we'll bring him there and leave him.
把他带过去然后丢在那里
He hasn't gained his memories back, right?
他还没恢复记忆呢吧
No.
嗯
Glad to hear that.
太好了呢
If you were told to get rid of the kid, what would you do?
如果让你处理掉这个孩子 你会怎么办
He will visit the Imperial Palace with his family.
预计和家人一同访问皇居
The next headline...
下一则新闻
Poor thing.
真可怜啊
You'll feel better soon.
马上就会好起来的
Mom and Dad are here for you.
爸爸妈妈都陪着你呢
It's alright.
没事的
I'll bring you breakfast.
我去拿早餐过来
I'm scared...
我好怕啊
You'll be safe.
你会得救的
Keep pretending you don't remember anything.
继续装作失忆
I know...
我…
who is behind this!
知道谁是最坏的人了
I want to see the editor of the "Truth Dynamite" magazine.
我想见一下《真相爆炸》这本杂志的编辑
Okay. May I ask who you are?
好的 请问客人您是
It's true that our magazine has published several special editions about this person...
我们杂志的确做过几期关于这个人的特刊
So this Kondo guy really exists?
也就是说 近藤这个人是真实存在的吧
Yeah, he does.
是的 确实有这么个人
We even got a tip lately claiming to have found Kondo's whereabouts.
最近还有关于近藤的所在地的情报
Eh? Where is it?
那是在哪里
Well, the informant asked for a big pay
那情报提供者索要了天价的情报费
which I wouldn't agree to.
我和他说了那不可能
I haven't contacted him ever since.
自那之后就没有再联络了
Excuse me, Otani-san?
不好意思 大谷先生
Have you seen our head editor?
看到编辑部长了吗
No, I haven't.
不 没有看到
Something happened to Kanae-chan?
香苗怎么了吗
She left a while ago, and I haven't been able to reach her since.
这个 刚才她出去之后就联系不上她了
But today is our deadline.
今天是截稿日啊
It's about time.
差不多该走了
Here's the kid's bag.
这是那孩子的包
Boy...
小朋友
Yes?
什么事
Ah, nothing.
不 没什么
Hello?
是
Leave the kid there, and your job is done.
把孩子放下以后工作就结束了
Thank you for your service.
辛苦了
Was it worth it going out of your way
特意恐吓我
to threaten me?
就是为了这件事吗
Hey!
喂喂
Stop pretending to be some legendary hitman.
我已经知道了 你根本算不上什么传说中的杀手
I know you're just a fraud that lets people go.
你不过是个专门放人走的家伙罢了
People like you are only suited to running errands.
跑腿这种事对你来说正好
Don't be so smug!
别太自以为是
Leave the kid at the event
把孩子放到会场后
and keep watching until someone finds him.
一直看着他直到有人保护他为止
If the police get involved,
要是被警察发现了
you'll be held accountable.
你得负责
Even a small fry can complete this simple job.
这种事就算是小混混也能做到
Oji-san, I need to pee.
叔叔 我想尿尿
Oh, okay.
啊 知道了
There's a bomb in my bag.
那个背包里放了炸弹
It's the remote-controlled type,
因为是远程操作
so the plan is probably to trigger it at a certain time.
所以大概是打算在某处看准时机按下开关吧
How did you...
为什么
I didn't have any Kamen Yaiba exhibit ticket.
我可没有带着什么假面超人展的门票
I don't know what the aim is yet,
虽然现在还不知道对方的目的是什么
but I've pretty much figured out everything else.
但后面的事基本能够猜得到
You're the famous Kondo, right?
叔叔你就是那个传说中的近藤吧
I read about you in a magazine.
我有在杂志上看到过
Yea.
是啊
But you're actually someone that lets your targets go.
但你其实只是专门放人走而已
That's right.
是的
I knew it.
果然是这样
A while back, my father helped investigate a case that seemed related to Kondo.
我爸爸曾经协助过一件据说和近藤有关的案子
He told me
他曾说
that after Kondo received a request to kill someone,
近藤很可能在收到杀人的委托后
he would tell the target the truth
就会把实情告诉目标人物
and receive payment from both sides,
然后收取两方的酬金
pretending he had killed the target
假装已经杀了目标人物
while secretly letting the person escape.
实际却放跑了那个人
But there wasn't any evidence.
虽然没有证据
You're right.
就是这样
So, if anyone found out
那么 这个实情如果被人知道了
that those targets are still alive, everything would be brought to light.
本该已死的人还活着的事就会暴露
You're being blackmailed over this, right?
叔叔就是因为这个被威胁了吧
Yeah.
嗯
Who exactly are you?
你到底是
I am Conan Edogawa.
我叫江户川柯南
A detective.
是个侦探
A detective?
侦探？
The real bad guy should be
最坏的那个人应该就是
that "Ad-libbing Tatsu."
即兴表演龙
Yesterday, at the bath house,
昨天在澡堂
I saw a suspicious man who washed his upper body 3 times
有个光洗上身就洗了三遍
and kept watching the lockers.
而且还一直注意着柜子的可疑男人
Hey, are you done yet?
好了吗
I need a little longer.
还有一会儿
I became suspicious, so I went to the locker room
我有些怀疑 就去更衣室看了看
and saw you sitting there reading the newspaper.
然后就看到叔叔你坐在那里看报
You weren't wet at all,
身体一点都没有湿
so I immediately sensed that something was wrong.
一看就知道有问题
I was just wondering what it was
正好奇是怎么回事
when that guy called Tatsu came in
那个叫龙的人就进来了
and took the locker key from his pocket.
因为他从口袋里拿出了柜子的钥匙
So I went to talk to him without thinking much.
所以我没多想就过去搭话了
Then I saw the cookie cans in the locker.
然后就看到柜子里有个曲奇罐
I wasn't wearing anything at the time,
我没有穿衣服
but there were 3 suspicious people around.
而可疑的人却有三人之多
The situation was unfavorable to me, so I took my cell phone and transmitter just to be safe.
我觉得情况对我不利 就打算先拿手机和发信器
Transmitter?
发信器？
Yeah! It's a sticker,
嗯 就像一张贴纸一样
so you can stick it anywhere.
什么地方都可以贴
And these glasses work as a receiver.
然后这个眼镜就是收信器
There's a radar installed.
还有雷达
Little boy,
小朋友
did you come here alone?
你是一个人来的吗
Conan-kun!
柯南
Do you feel lonely there all by yourself?
你一个人会不会很孤单啊
I'm doing fine!
没关系
I just met someone I know!
刚刚遇见了一个认识的哥哥
Anyway, I stuck the transmitter on his jacket,
我把发信器贴在了他的外套上
and was planning to contact someone else later.
虽然想联系别人
But I was running out of time,
但是没有那个时间了
so I intentionally slipped
所以我故意摔倒
to cause a stir.
想要引起骚动
And after that...
然后
Are you okay, boy?
小朋友 你没事吧
I was drugged
我被迫吸入了迷药
and lost consciousness for real.
就真的失去了意识
Drugged?
迷药？
Yeah.
嗯
It means they were planning to attack someone in the bath house all along.
也就是说本来就是想在那里袭击某个人
Probably...
应该就是这样吧
Yes, it must've been me.
这个啊 是我吧
They put me there to keep watch
故意让我在那里监视
with the intention of assaulting me.
就是为了袭击我
They were planning to kidnap you while you were undressed and unconscious,
强行拉走一个全裸的没有抵抗力的大叔
and then...
然后呢
Let me be the scapegoat for all the crimes, probably.
制定这些计划大概是为了让我背黑锅吧
But if that was the original plan, wouldn't that be a bit rash?
但是如果说这是原来的计划 也太粗糙了
After all,
首先
the police had already found the bombs,
炸弹被警察发现了
and my presence at the bath house was just a coincidence.
而当时我也只是恰好在澡堂
It seems to be a last-minute makeshift plan.
这只能被认为是走投无路所以临时改变了计划
And that's the ad-libbing, right?
也就是即兴表演吧
So you think that "Ad-libber Tatsu" was the mastermind?
所以 你说即兴表演龙就是主犯
But...
可是
He was supposed to have died at that factory.
那个人应该死在工厂里了
But
但是
the news only reported the discovery of one unidentified body.
新闻里只报道说发现了身份不明的尸体
If Tatsu's body had been found with the other man's,
如果是龙和另外一个大叔的尸体都在的话
two bodies should have been reported.
应该会说有两具尸体吧
That's why I checked with the glasses
于是我就用眼镜进行了追踪
and found that "Ad-libber Tatsu"
发现即兴表演龙
was moving.
正在移动中
I know
我…
who is behind this!
知道谁是最坏的人了
He's currently inside that house.
现在就在那个家里
I'll buy you some time.
我会争取时间的
Confirm Tatsu's location and call the police, Oji-san.
叔叔你确认了龙的位置之后就报警
Understood.
知道了
Now, the only thing left is that bomb...
接下来就是怎么处理炸弹的问题了
I'll take care of that.
我会想办法的
Please do.
拜托了
Also,
还有一件事
my friends may have been captured by them.
我的同伴可能被抓住了
Friends?
同伴？
You have her?
抓到了吗
Yeah. I said that I wanted to talk about her husband and she fell for it right away.
嗯 我一说有些关于她丈夫的话要跟她说 她马上就来了
She's sleeping in the room now.
现在就睡在屋里
But is this really necessary?
但是有必要做到这一步吗
I'm a cautious person.
我可是很胆小的
Anyway, come back here first.
总之你也快回这边来
I'm on my way now.
正赶过去
Understood.
知道了
Feeling a bit cold?
是不是有点冷
Why do I have to help?
为什么我必须要这么做啊
I'll explain later.
我之后会跟你解释的
You owe me one anyway.
你还欠我人情
Don't forget, I was the one who let you go last time.
忘了我之前放你逃走了吗
I'm busy today.
今天不太行啊
I have to take care of my cat and some other stuff as well.
我还要照顾小猫 有很多事啊
There's no one I can trust other than you!
我能信任的人只有你了
You have pathetically few friends, don't you?
你的朋友是有多少啊
You'll be connected to voicemail.
这是电话留言服务
She's still working?
还在工作吗
Hello?
喂
Seriously,
真是的
what on earth is going on?
到底怎么回事啊
Who are you?
喂 你是谁
Jeez.
真是的
That's dangerous!
很危险的啊
What are you doing?
你在做什么
I was in an accident.
出车祸了
Could you give me a ride?
可以载我一程吗
Calm down.
请放心
That boy told me everything.
事情经过我已经听那个少年说了
Here they come!
来了来了
15 meters to go!
还有15米
It'll explode as soon as I press this button!
按下这里就会砰的一下爆炸了
2 meters.
2米
1 meter.
1米
It really exploded...
真的发生爆炸了
What did the warning say?
预告是怎么说的
That there was a bomb, so we should evacuate the residents.
只说了这里有炸弹 迅速疏散周围居民
What?
什么
What's going on?
怎么回事
Why didn't it explode?
为什么没有爆炸
Damn it!
可恶
Just give up!
没用的
You...
是你
Don't move.
别动
Ai-kun, are you alright?
小哀 你没事吧
Professor!
博士
Can I borrow it?
也借我玩一下
Conan-kun,
柯南
are you alright?
你没事吧
Hello.
嗯
Everything's fine.
已经没事了
Your friends are safe.
你的同伴也都安全了
I know who their targets are.
我已经知道他们的目标了
He can't be forgiven.
不可原谅
Is Tatsu there?
龙在那边吗
No, he's not.
没在
Hey, Conan-kun!
我说柯南
Ran-neechan, what are you doing here?
小兰姐姐 你怎么在这里
What do you mean?
你还问我为什么
I'm going to look for him.
我现在就去找
I came here to find you!
我就是来找你才到这里来的呀
Shinichi is here too, right?
新一也和你在一起吧
Where is he?
新一在哪里
There's a bomb!
有炸弹
Everybody, run!
大家快跑啊
Ran-neechan, hurry!
小兰姐姐也快跑
Wait a moment, Conan-kun!
等 等一下柯南
Everybody, run, hurry!
快点 大家快跑
Run!
快跑
Ah, wait a moment...
啊 等等
It's dangerous here!
这里很危险
Let's go!
快走
Where's Tatsu?
龙在哪里
I don't know.
我不知道
I really don't know!
我真的不知道
He was supposed to come here,
本来应该在这里的
but he said he had something else to do and would come later.
不过他有别的工作耽误了
He's not coming.
不会来了
You, too, were only used by him.
你也只是被他利用了而已
Once the job is done, he'll kill you, too!
达到最终目的后你也会被杀掉的
The evidence is on the ceiling of the basement.
证据就在地下室的天花板上
He says he wants to talk to you.
他说想和你说话
Idiot, look at what you've done.
你还真是做了愚蠢的事
Did you think that you'd get away with it
以为把自己的工作室炸了
just by blowing up your workroom?
就能和过去一刀两断吗
I'm not sure who the idiot is here.
到底是谁在做蠢事
The "Ad-libbing Tatsu" I know
我所知道的即兴表演龙
is supposed to be someone who engages in smaller jobs.
应该是个低调地做些小事的人
Your fiancee is such a pretty woman.
你的太太还真是漂亮啊
What?
什么
Are these two your friends?
这些人是你的同伴吗
Trying to quit the gang for the woman you love.
迷上了女人就急急忙忙从黑道退出来
You really thought it'd be that easy?
你想得太好了吧
There are still things I want you to do.
我还要让你帮我做事呢
Play any more tricks,
要是你再有什么小动作
or get caught by the police,
或者因为疏忽被警察抓住
your fiancee dies!
你太太的命可就没了
Conan-kun!
柯南
Where are you, Conan-kun?
柯南你在哪里
Wake up!
起来
What is it?
什么
Hurry up and drive!
快点开车
Jeez, what now?
真是的 到底怎么回事
Was that...
刚才的 难道是
Dad?
爸爸
As expected,
果然和我想的一样
this is all Kondo's doing!
这绝对是近藤做的
That car!
那辆车
Hand it over!
快交出来
Keep an eye on them for now.
你先看住他们
Okay.
知道了
And you, come with me.
你跟我一起走
It's fine,
嗯 嗯 没事
there's still time.
还有时间
Yes, I'm counting on you.
嗯 拜托了
What's your relationship with Tatsu?
你和龙是什么关系
Actually, I was the one who found out
其实最开始发现你事情的人
about your secret.
是我哦
About a year ago, I happened to discover that revolving door.
大概一年前 我偶然发现了那扇回转门
you were in the middle of a job, right?
你那时正在工作吧
Hey, come here for a moment.
喂 过来一下
Hurry!
快点
Man!
真是的
Look, over there.
你看那个
Then Tatsu got interested and started investigating you.
他看到后对你产生了很大的兴趣 于是开始调查你
I see, so it's that kind of relationship.
原来是这样的关系
Got a problem with it?
不行吗
Turn left there.
啊 在那边左拐
Was it also you who left the file about the Red Brick Warehouse at my workroom yesterday?
我工作室里面红砖仓库的资料文件也是你昨天放的吧
Tatsu is quite smart!
那个人很聪明
Don't underestimate him.
还是不要小看他比较好
What's going on here?
这是怎么回事
You are such a naughty little boy.
真是个坏孩子
There are cameras everywhere around this house, you know?
这个屋子可是有隐藏很多摄像头的
- Is this idiot your friend? - Hey! Where did you go?
-这个笨蛋是你的朋友吗 -喂 到哪里去了
That hurts!
好疼
What the heck is happening?
这到底是怎么回事啊
Hey,
我说
I was just asked to give him a ride.
我只是受人所托
I have nothing to do with this!
我跟这些事根本没有任何关系啊
So...
所以
Shut your mouth, will you?
你能闭嘴吗
Don't shoot!
别开枪
So, can you explain this?
好了 你能给我解释解释吗
Ah, that's my cellphone!
啊 我的手机
This girl...
这个女人
She looks like...
好像是
Excuse me, is anyone home?
打扰一下 有人在家吗
Excuse me!
打扰一下
Conan-kun, are you there?
柯南 你在这吗
Shinichi!
新一
Ran-neechan, is it?
你是叫小兰姐姐吧
Conan-kun is inside.
柯南的话就在里面
Is that idiot with him, Shinichi?
和他在一起的笨蛋就是叫新一的家伙吧
Anyway, do as I...
总之你就乖乖地…
What just happened?
什 什么
There are bombs in that truck.
那辆卡车里装了炸弹
Get in and wait for orders.
我要你坐上车等待时机
You'll get detailed instructions later.
具体的我之后会给你指示
This is your last chance.
这可是你最后的机会了
Don't fail if you want to save your fiancee.
想救你太太就别失败了
He asked you to go back to that house on the mountain
他叫你在成功炸毁红砖仓库之后
after the bombing of the Red Brick Warehouse was successful, right?
回到那山上的屋子里去吧
He is going to silence you too, you know.
他是想把你也杀了
Don't you try to fool me! You are wasting your time!
就算你想编那种话来唬我也是没用的
Your fiance left you a voicemail on your cell phone.
有你丈夫的语音留言
This might be the last time you hear his voice,
这可能是你最后一次听他的声音了
so listen carefully.
要好好听哦
Hello.
喂
I'm sorry to bring it up out of the blue,
不好意思 突然和你说这样的话
but I can't see you for a while.
最近一段时间可能无法跟你见面
Due to my previous job, I have to go to the police station.
我因为过去的事必须去一趟警局
I don't know how that will end.
虽然不知道会发生什么
I won't expect you to wait for me.
我不会叫你等我
Anyway, I just want to say
但是我想说
that being able to meet someone like you after I've led such a shameful life is really my fortune.
在我这糟糕透顶的人生中能够遇到你真的三生有幸
I'm grateful.
谢谢你
End of message. End of...
语音到此结束
If he hadn't met you,
如果没有遇到你
he might've stayed a criminal and enjoyed himself for the rest of his life.
那个男人可能会一直当一个无名小混混  幸福地度过他的一生
It's a pity that you ruined that for him!
真是红颜祸水啊
The madam wants to know when they can leave.
夫人想问她什么时候才能回去
We're still making sure the area is safe.
现在还在确认安全情况
Please wait a little longer.
请稍等一会
Ready, Kondo-san?
准备好了吗 近藤先生
What do you want me to do?
你想让我做什么
The car carrying the children of Nihorika's Prime Minister
尼保利加国首相的孩子们乘坐的车子
will be crossing that bridge ahead of you.
过会就会从你前面的桥上通过
I want you to crash into that car and cause an accident.
你开车过去引发事故
I'll detonate the bombs.
我会引爆炸弹
Why target the children?
为什么要袭击孩子们
That's the job I was hired to do,
这是雇主的意思
to blow them up with bombs.
我用炸弹炸飞他们就行了
It's just business.
这只是一场交易
What's more, this request was originally meant for you.
而且他们本来找的是你
What?
什么
Since I was interested in you,
因为对你感兴趣
I snuck into your workroom.
我曾偷偷潜入你的工作室
I was shocked
可真是让我吃惊啊
that the legendary Kondo really existed.
传说中的近藤竟然真的存在
But through thorough investigation,
但经过详细调查
I found that Kondo had never killed a single soul.
我发现近藤居然一个人都没有杀过
Instead, he was just a sneaky liar who set his targets free.
相反只是个专门放人跑的阴险家伙
And at that moment...
正在那时
It was a request from overseas.
有个国外的委托
They'd been looking for the best hitman in Japan,
好像是在找日本头号杀手
and finally found your contact.
说是好不容易才联系到你
You... accepted that request?
你接受了这个委托
Yeah. The payment was generous, after all.
对 因为这报酬可是相当丰厚啊
I gave them my number and accepted the request.
我把自己的电话告诉对方 接下了这笔生意
Your meticulously compiled most-wanted criminal list
你辛苦整理的那些要犯的名单
was of a great help to me.
可帮了我的大忙
Time to move.
差不多该出发了
Drive straight to the bridge.
到桥的那边去
Don't hang up.
别挂电话
Damn it!
可恶
A little further!
就快到了
Hey...
喂
What are you doing?
怎 怎么了
Didn't I tell you to go back to the house?
不是跟你说让你回那个屋子去吗
That guy doesn't have his cellphone!
那家伙没有拿手机
He said that he'd given it to that boy
因为他说自己的手机在红砖仓库
at the Red Brick Warehouse,
已经交给那个孩子了
so I gave him mine.
我就把自己的给他了
So if you want to contact him, call my cellphone.
所以要联系他就打我的电话
I wanted to hurry over to tell you, but there were so many checkpoints along the way.
我想着必须早点告诉你 但到处都有警察盘问
But I was just...
但是刚才
Freeze! Police!
别动 警察
Wh-What?
为 为什么
Just surrender!
死心吧
This job's too much for you to handle.
这笔生意对你来说还是太大了
By the way, that whole conversation earlier has been recorded as evidence.
对了 刚才的对话我已经录下来了 这是最有力的证据
But how did you find this place?
你是怎么知道这里的
Hey! Who are you talking to?
喂 你在和谁说话
Hello?
喂
Hold it!
等等
You can't come here!
不能靠近
Let me pass, please!
拜托让我过去吧
Are you a resident of that apartment?
你是那个公寓的人吗
No, I'm not, but...
不 我不是
Hey, officer!
警察叔叔
He's the fiance of the female hostage.
这个叔叔是那个女人质的丈夫
Really?
真的吗
Yes.
嗯 是的
I see, why didn't you say so earlier?
什么啊 那就早点说嘛
Your fiancee is fine.
你太太没事
She'll be coming down very soon. Please go ahead.
我想很快就会下来 快过去吧
Thank you.
谢谢
The one who planted the transmitter on Nana was you, wasn't it, Oji-san?
在那个叫娜娜的女人身上装了发信器的人是你吧 叔叔
Yeah.
是啊
Quick, call the police!
快叫警察
There are bombs in the basement!
下面有炸弹
What?
什么
Hey, Conan-kun,
我说柯南
could you tell us what's going on?
解释一下这到底是怎么回事啊
It's moving.
在动
Onii-san!
大哥哥
What?
什么
Found it!
找到了
Onii-san! Follow that light blue car!
大哥哥 那辆淡蓝色的车
Ready,
准备好了吗
Kondo-san?
近藤先生
What do you want me to do?
你想让我做什么
I see.
原来是这样
What about the bombs in the truck?
炸弹呢
I delivered them to the police.
交给警察了
Ah, hello, is this the police?
啊 喂 警察先生吗
I...I found some bombs.
我 我发现炸弹了
Yes, hidden in cookie cans.
是的 装在曲奇罐里
Yes.
是
Really? But how did you know he was here?
但你是怎么知道他在这边的
Tatsu found out very quickly that my workroom had been blown up.
那个工作室爆炸后龙很快就知道了
I thought he should be hiding somewhere he could see my workroom,
我认为他至少得在能看得到那工作室的地方
so I tried my luck.
所以就赌了一把
As expected of the legendary Kondo-san.
不愧是传说中的近藤先生
Ah?
啊
Like I said, I don't know anything!
所以说我什么都不知道
A friend asked me to drive that kid
只是被认识的人拜托了
to the Kamen Yaiba exhibit. That's all!
送小孩子到假面超人展去而已
Hey, kid!
小朋友
It's dangerous. You shouldn't be around here.
这边很危险 不要进来哦
Do you live nearby?
你是附近的孩子吗
Yeah! Sorry!
嗯 对不起
Hey!
我说你
Would you explain it to them?
你也帮我解释解释啊
The police won't listen to a word I say!
这些家伙根本就说不通啊
Who was that man with Conan-kun just now?
刚才和柯南在一起的男人是谁
No idea.
不认识
Oh.
这样啊
So where on earth has Shinichi gone!
所以 新一到底在哪里啊
This whole thing has been such a mess!
真是一头雾水
Everyone, let me explain!
各位 听我说
All this was done by that legendary hitman Kondo.
这一切都是传说中的杀手近藤所为
Speaking of which, the reason I got involved in this is...
我最早和这个事件扯上关系就是
The police department believes that the smuggled bombs discovered several days ago in Haido-cho
关于前几天在杯户街发现的走私炸弹一事
are related to higher ups in the Arasen government,
警方认为与阿拉森国的政府高级官员有关
and will contact them through their embassy...
现正通过外交手段…
Please!
拜托了
Let me turn back into Shinichi this time!
就这一次 让我变回新一吧
No.
不行
Don't say that! I'm begging you!
别这么说嘛 拜托了
I can't figure out any logical excuse
为什么小兰会收到新一的短信
to explain why Ran got a text from Shinichi.
我实在想不出什么好借口
That wouldn't change regardless, right?
变回来了不也一样吗
No way!
没那回事啦
Please, give me the antidote!
拜托了 把药给我
No. I Won't.
不可能
Stingy.
小气鬼
It's for your own good.
这是为你好
Fine.
没办法
I'll just have to think of a plausible excuse then.
只能想个好借口了
Ah, and...
啊 还有
Huh?
嗯？
Thank you
谢了啊
for looking for me even though you were in such bad shape.
都变成这副样子了还来找我
It's nothing.
没什么
Yeah, this looks terrible.
嗯 这还真是惨
I forget that the bath hasn't been fixed yet!
我忘了浴室坏了
What should I do?
怎么办啊
Even with that shrunken body, he's still doing his best!
还是一样的人小拼劲十足嘛
And next,
那么接下来
it'll be the new year soon.
马上就是新年了
I should also head for new horizons and accept new challenges!
我也来进行一些新的挑战吧
Coming April 2015,
2015年4月上映
the Detective Conan movie -
剧场版名侦探柯南
Sunflowers of Inferno!
业火的向日葵
Prepare for a whole new experience!
这次可不同以往啊